To survive in a world at war, he must find a strength
greater than all the events that surround him.
Empire of the Sun is a drama, history, war film directed by Steven Spielberg.
Jamie Graham, a privileged English boy, is living in Shanghai when the
Japanese invade and force all foreigners into prison camps.
Jamie is captured with an American sailor, who looks out
for him while they are in the camp together.
Even though he is separated from his parents and in a hostile environment, Jamie maintains his dignity
and youthful spirit, providing a beacon of hope for the others held captive with him.
Jim, played by Christian Bale.
Basie, played by John Malkovich.
Mrs. Victor, played by Miranda Richardson.
Dr. Rawlins, played by Nigel Havers.
Frank Demarest, played by Joe Pantoliano.
Maxton, played by Leslie Phillips.
Empire of the Sun is a 1987 American epic coming-of-age war drama film directed
by Steven Spielberg and written by Tom Stoppard, based on J.
Ballard's semi-autobiographical 1984 novel of the same name.
The film tells the story of Jamie "Jim" Graham (Christian Bale), a young boy who goes from living with his wealthy British
family in Shanghai to becoming a prisoner of war in an internment camp operated by the Japanese during World War II.
The film also stars John Malkovich, Miranda Richardson, Nigel Havers, Joe
Pantoliano, Masatō Ibu, Leslie Phillips, Ben Stiller, and Robert Stephens.
Harold Becker and David Lean were originally to direct before
Spielberg came on board, initially as a producer for Lean.
Spielberg was attracted to directing the film because of a personal
connection to Lean's films and World War II topics.
He considers it to be his most profound work on "the loss of innocence".
The film received positive reviews, with praise towards Bale's performance, the
cinematography, the visuals, Williams's score and Spielberg's direction.
However, the film was not initially a commercial success, earning only $22 million at the US box office, although it
eventually more than recouped its budget through revenues in foreign markets, home video, and television.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
shanghai, china, atomic bomb, stadium, bravery.
The tone is emotional.